A Guide to the Luther Porter Jackson Papers, 1772-1960
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
- SERIES VII. MATERIALS WRITTEN BY LUTHER P. JACKSON, SR.
  - A. Feature articles written by Luther Porter Jackson in the (Norfolk, Virginia) Journal and Guide, under the general heading, "Rights and Duties in a Democracy".
    - "The Opportunities of Negro College Professors For Research In The South" May 17, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1617)
    - "The Virginia State Teachers Association" May 25, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1617)
    - "The Bugaboo of Negro Voting Activity" May 31, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1617)
    - "Winning Victories But Standing Still" June 8, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1618)
    - "Winning Victories But Standing Still" (2) June 11, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1618)
    - "Winning Victories But Standing Still" (3) June 19, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1618)
    - "The Bugaboo of Negro Voting Activity" (2) June 21, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1618)
    - "The Awakening In Southampton County Virginia" July 4, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1619)
    - "The Annual Conference of The National ASSN For The Advancement of Colored People" July 13, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1619)
    - "Summer School Teaching In Our Colleges" July 19, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1619)
    - "Equal Salaries For Teachers In North Carolina" July 24, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1619)
    - "Equal Salaries In North Carolina" (2) Aug. 1, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1620)
    - "Teaching American Government At Virginia State College" Aug. 11, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1620)
    - "The Riddle of The Parties" Aug. 16, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1620)
    - "The Riddles of Parties" (2) Aug. 24, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1620)
    - "Strange As It Seems" Aug. 30, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1620)
    - "Poll Tax Repeal And The Negro In Virginia" Sept. 6, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1621)
    - "Poll Tax Repeal And The Negro In Virginia" (2) Sept. 13, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1621)
    - "Register For Voting" Sept. 21, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1621)
    - "The Awakening In Cumberland County, Virginia" Sept. 28, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1621)
    - "Roosevelt, Dewey, and The Negro" Oct. 5, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1622)
    - "Melvin Alston: A Tribute" Oct. 15, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1622)
    - "The Non-Voting Tradition Among Negro School Teachers" Oct. 23, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1622)
    - "The Boston Meeting Of The Association For The Study Of Negro Life and History" Nov. 1, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1623)
    - "The Meaning of Election Day" Nov. 3, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1623)
    - "The Negro Soldier In The Civil War" Nov. 16, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1623)
    - "The Case of Silas Rogers" Nov. 22, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1623)
    - "The Opportunity To Abolish The Poll Tax In Virginia" Nov 30, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1623)
    - "The Opportunity To Abolish The Poll Tax" (2) Dec. 5, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1624)
    - "Civic Celebration In Slavery Days" Dec. 14, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1624)
    - "Christmas Celebration In Slavery Days" Dec. 21, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1624)
    - "Balance Sheet In Race Relations For 1944" Dec. 28, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1624)
    - "The Teacher Salary Fight The Hope For the Future" Jan. 1, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1625)
    - "The Teaching Of Negro History At Hampton Institute" Jan. 9, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1625)
    - "Hampton, Virginia In the Days of Old" Jan 18, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1625)
    - "Founders Day At Virginia State College" Jan. 24, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1625)
    - "Office Holding In Bygone Days" Jan. 26, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1625)
    - "Peter J. Carter of Northampton County, Virginia" Feb. 8, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1626)
    - "B. J. Johnson, The Vote Conscious Minister of Atlanta, Georgia" Feb. 15, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1626)
    - "The Negro Newspaper In Dispensable Aid For Negro History" Feb. 22, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1626)
    - "The Negro Newspaper Aid For" Feb. 28, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1626)
    - "Class Division Within The Negro Race" March 13, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1627)
    - "The Pool Tax Our First Obligation" March 21, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1627)
    - "The Promise of The War" March 28, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1627)
    - "The Fifth Annual Report of The Virginia Voters League" April 4, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1628)
    - "Saving Family Papers" April 11, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1628)
    - "Franklin D. Roosevelt Friend of the Common People" April 18, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1628)
    - "We Must Get Ready For The Election In 1945 and 1946" April 25, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1628)
    - "Honor To The Teachers of Virginia" May 2, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1629)
    - "Abolish The Poll Tax Then What?"(2) May 16, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1629)
    - "Reverend Williams B. Ball: Candidate For The Virginia Legislature" May 23, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1629)
    - "The Teacher Salary Fight In Newport News" May 30, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1629)
    - "The Teacher Salary Fight In Newport News" (2) June 6, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1630)
    - "Whites and Negroes Indifferent Just Alike" June 12, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1630)
    - "Slave Advertisements In Old Newspapers" June 19, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1630)
    - "The Contributions of The Negro Lawyer" June 26, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1630)
    - "The Contribution of The Negro Lawyer" (2) July 4, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1631)
    - "The Election In Virginia On August 7th: An Opportunity For Everybody" July 11, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1631)
    - "Getting Ready To Vote In Richmond, Virginia" July 18, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1631)
    - "Sixteen Model Ministers" July 25, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1631)
    - "Labeling The Negro Race" Aug. 1, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1632)
    - "Southern Whites Rallying To The Negro" Aug. 8, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1632)
    - "The First Protest In Virginia Against Jim Crow" Aug. 15, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1632)
    - "The Negro In Our History" -- A Notable Book Aug. 22, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1632)
    - "John Mitchell: Anti-Lynching Apostle" Aug. 28, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1632)
    - "The Victory At Newport News" Sept. 5, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1633)
    - "Spending A Pleasant Vacation" Sept. 12, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1633)
    - (Box-folder 65:1633)
    - "The Opportunities of Our College For Community Uplift" Sept. 19, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1633)
    - "The Whole Loaf or Half A Loaf?" Sept. 26, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1633)
    - "The Coming of Camilla Williams to Virginia State College" Oct. 3, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1634)
    - "Southern White Soldiers On The Race Question" Oct. 10, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1634)
    - "Virginia's War Dead Who Are They?" Oct. 17, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1634)
    - "Virginia's War Dead Who Are They? II" Oct. 24, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1634)
    - "Thomas H. Reid: A Candidate For The Virginia Legislature" Oct 31, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1634)
    - "Office holding An Incentive To Voting" Nov. 6, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1635)
    - "The Drive For Registerated Voters In Atlanta, Georgia" Nov. 14, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1635)
    - "Striving For A Better Deal in Fairfax County, Virginia" Nov. 21, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1635)
    - "Raising Money From Teachers Associations" Nov. 28, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1635)
    - "Membership Fees In State Teachers Associations" Dec. 5, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1636)
    - "The Passing of An Old Citizen: George W. Lewis" Dec. 11, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1636)
    - "Handel's "Messiah" A Fitting Observance Of Christmastide" Dec. 19, 1945 (Box-folder 65:1636)
    - "The March Of Dimes" Jan. 8, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1637)
    - "Bernad A. Coles: Candidate For Office In Charlottesville, Va." Jan. 21, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1637)
    - "Negro Officeholders In Virginia" -- A Production Of Many People" Jan. 30, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1637)
    - "Ballad T. Edwards: Competent Officeholder And Notable Citizen" Feb. 6, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1638)
    - "Senator Williams N. Stevens" Feb. 13, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1638)
    - "Henry Williams- Minister in Politics" Feb. 20, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1638)
    - "Freedom's Journal" -- The First Negro Newspaper Feb. 27, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1638)
    - "A New Day On The Way" March 5, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1639)
    - "Changing The Name Of A College" March 13, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1639)
    - "The Cracking Of The Solid South" March 27, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1639)
    - "The Handbook On The Voting Status Of Negroes In Virginia" April 4, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1640)
    - "The Reverend S.F. Daly And Voting Opportunities In North Carolina" April 10, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1640)
    - "The Virginia Association For Education And The Virginia General Assembly" April 17, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1640)
    - "The Registrar: The Bugbear Of Many Negro Citizens" April 22, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1640)
    - "1946: The Year Of Opportunity" April 30, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1640)
    - "Meeting With Success In Suffolk, Virginia" May 6, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1641)
    - "How To Get Funds For The Support Of Public Schools" May 14, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1641)
    - "Negro Colleges Shaping The Careers Of There Music Graduates" May 21, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1641)
    - "Reasons For The In activity Of Negroes In Political Affairs" May 29, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1641)
    - "Reasons For The Inactivity Of Negroes In Political Affairs" (2) June 5, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1642)
    - "The Case Of Irene Morgan: A Victory For Negro Lawyers" June 12, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1642)
    - "An Open Letter To The Veterans and Non-Registered Poll Tax Payers Of Virginia" June 19, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1642)
    - "Thurgood Marshall: Winner Of The Spring Medal" June 26, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1642)
    - "Seeking Office In Virginia During 1945-46" July 3, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1643)
    - "Segregation: Will It Last Always?" July 9, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1643)
    - "Congressman Powell And The Daughters Of The American Revolution" July 18, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1643)
    - "Georgia Ahead-Virginia Behind" July 24, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1643)
    - "The Centennial of the Independence of Liberia" July 30, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1643)
    - "Carrying Voters Acquiring Land In The 17th & 18th Centuries" Aug. 7, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1644)
    - "Free Negroes Acquiring Town Lots In The Period 1780-1800" Aug. 14, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1644)
    - "Property Owned By Virginia Free Negroes In 1860" Aug. 27, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1644)
    - "Husbands Buying Their Wives And Wives Buying Their Husbands" Sept. 4, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1645)
    - "Heavy Voting On Election Day In Suffolk And Nansemond County, Virginia" Sept. 11, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1645)
    - "Handling Down The Knowledge Of Bricklaying Trade" Sept 18, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1645)
    - "The Lack Of Knowledge The Fundamentals Among College Students" Sept 24, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1645)
    - (Box-folder 65:1645)
    - "The Lack Of Knowledge Of The Fundamentals Among College Students" (2) Oct. 2, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1646)
    - "The Address Of Roberts P. Daniel At Virginia State College" Oct. 9, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1646)
    - "The Battle For Ballot In The Deep South" Oct. 16, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1646)
    - "A. McKee Banks: Meeting The Needs Of The People Of Caroline County For Food" Oct. 23, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1646)
    - "Negro History Research: Its Needs Shortcomings" Oct. 30, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1646)
    - "Charles S. Johnson: Symbol Of A Changing Leadership In Negro Education" Nov. 6, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1647)
    - (Box-folder 65:1647)
    - "The Reverend Robert L. Taylor: Advocating A Life Of Civic Participation By Church Members" Nov. 13, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1647)
    - "A Century Of The American Missionary Association" Nov. 20, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1647)
    - "Something Fundamentally Wrong With America" Nov. 27, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1647)
    - "Memorial To Otelia Shields Howard" Dec. 4, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1648)
    - "The Campagain To Oust Bilbo" Dec. 11, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1648)
    - "A Christmas Message To All People" Dec. 17, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1648)
    - "1946: The Year Of the Rebirth Of The Negro In Southern Elections" Dec. 26, 1946 (Box-folder 65:1648)
    - "New Year's Resolutions Of John Doe" Jan. 1, 1947 (Box-folder 65:1649)
    - "Gloucester County, Virginia: Its Advances And Its Shortcomings" Jan. 8, 1947 (Box-folder 65:1649)
    - "The Virginia Seminary & College And Its New President" Jan. 15, 1947 (Box-folder 65:1649)
    - "March 14,1947- Joseph Jenkins Roberts Day" Jan. 22, 1947 (Box-folder 65:1649)
    - "Samuel P. Bolling: A Character For Negro History Week" Jan. 29, 1947 (Box-folder 65:1649)
    - "Daniel M. Norton: Another Character For Negro History Week" Feb. 5,1947 (Box-folder 66:1650)
    - "Which Way Shall We Go: To The Polls Or To Courts?" Feb. 12,1947 (Box-folder 66:1650)
    - "March 14, 1947: Joseph Jenkins Roberts Day" Feb. 18, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1650)
    - "The Task Which Lies Ahead of Us" Feb. 26, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1650)
    - "The Task Which Lies Ahead of Us"(2) March 5, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1651)
    - "The Family Choir of Franklin, Virginia" March 19, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1651)
    - "Signs of An Awakening For Voting In The Deep South" March 26, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1651)
    - "The Campaign In Virginia For Registered Voters" April 2, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1652)
    - "Oliver W. Hill: Candidate For The Virginia Legislature" April 9, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1652)
    - "The Past, Present, And Future Of The Negro In Politics" April 16, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1652)
    - "The Drive To Convert The Virginia Teachers Non-Voters To Voters" April 23, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1652)
    - "The Appointment of W. Lester Banks, A Milestone in the Fire of the N.A.A.C.P. in Virginia" April 30, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1652)
    - "The Appointment of W. Lester Banks, A Milestone In The Fire of The N.A.A.C.P." May 7, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1653)
    - "Hampton, Virginia: In Politics Not What Used To Be" May 14, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1653)
    - "Ethel Thompson Overby: Civic Conscious School Principal" May 21, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1653)
    - "What good is a college degree?" May 28, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1653)
    - "Honorary Degree In American College" June 4, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1654)
    - "Rights and Duties in a Democracy" June 11, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1654)
    - "First Class Citizenship And second Class Citizenship" June 26, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1654)
    - "The False Beliefs of Teachers About Voting" July 3, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1655)
    - "The Rising Birth Rate of Children At Virginia State College" July 10, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1655)
    - "The Suffrage Situation In South Carolina" July 17, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1655)
    - "The Cracking of the Color line in Certain Southern Libraries" July 24, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1655)
    - "Ministers of The Gospel And The Voting Movement" July 31, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1655)
    - "The Campaign of Oliver W. Hill For The Virginia Legislature" Aug. 7, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1656)
    - "Arthur Lee: Progressive Negro Artisan of Salary Days" Aug. 14, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1656)
    - "A Continuation of The Story of Arthur Lee" Aug. 21, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1656)
    - "Raising Money For The Association For The Study of Negro Life And History" Sept. 3, 1947 (Box-folder 66:165)
    - "Twenty-Five Years At Virginia State College" Sept. 12, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1657)
    - "Rights And Duties In A Democracy" Sept. 19, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1657)
    - "John Hope Franklin And His New Book On Negro History" Sept. 25, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1657)
    - "Travel By Train In Southern States Better Now Than Years Ago" Oct. 2, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1658)
    - "A Football Game of Thirty-Seven Years Ago: Fisk University Defeats Morehouse College, 5 to 10" Oct. 15, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1658)
    - "Negro Voting: A Leading Topic In The Newspapers" Oct. 23, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1658)
    - "Oklahoma City, Oklahoma: Meeting Place of The Association For The Study of Negro Life And History" Oct. 30, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1658)
    - "What to do About The Civil Rights of Negroes" Nov. 6, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1659)
    - "The Election of William A. Lawrence To Office In Nansemond County, Virginia" Nov. 13, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1659)
    - "The Failure of Dr. C. S. Franklin To Win Office In Charles City County, Virginia" Nov. 20, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1659)
    - "The Call To Pay The Poll Tax" Nov. 26, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1659)
    - "A Tribute To Certain Persona In The Virginia State Department of Education" Dec. 4, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1660)
    - "Politics: A Game In Which Every Man Must Participate" Dec. 11, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1660)
    - "The Virginia Organization For Civil Rights: Serving To Wipe Out Segregation" Dec. 17, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1660)
    - "The Raise of "V-GRO" To Wipe Out "Jim Crow" Dec. 24, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1660)
    - "New Year's Resolutions of John Doe" Dec. 31, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1660)
    - "The Failure of The Negroes In The Fourth Congressional District of Virginia" Jan. 8, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1661)
    - "The Voting Status of Colored People In The Fourth Congressional District of Virginia" Jan. 22, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1661)
    - "The Voting Status of Colored People In The Fourth Congressional District of Virginia" Jan. 29, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1661)
    - "Raymond J. Valentine: Candidate For The City Council In Petersburg, Virginia" Feb. 5, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1662)
    - "The Views of Abraham Lincoln On The Race Questions" Feb. 12, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1662)
    - "The Fight On Slavery And Segregation, 1848-1948" Feb. 20, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1662)
    - "The Virginia Fight On Certain of Her Jim Crow Laws" Feb. 27, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1662)
    - "The Virginia Fight On Certain of Her Jim Crow Laws" March 5, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1663)
    - "Supporting Candidates For Office" March 12, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1663)
    - "The Views of Southern white People On the Segregation Laws" April 2, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1664)
    - "The Time It Will Take To Gain Equality Education" April 16, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1664)
    - "Rights And Duties In A Democracy" April 23, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1664)
    - "The Gold Star Honor Roll of Virginians In The Second World War" April 30, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1664)
    - "Harry P. Johnson: Candidate For The Town Council of McKenney, Virginia" May 6, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1665)
    - "The Drive in Virginia To Get The Teachers Qualified To Vote" May 13, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1665)
    - "Advice to the June college graduates of 1948" May 21, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1665)
    - "Pertinent Advice to the 1948 June College Graduates"(2) May 28, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1665)
    - "A Call For Readers To write Members of Congress Urging The Passage of The Bill For Federal Aid To Education" June 4, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1666)
    - "Thurgood Marshall: Recipient of The Honorary Degree of Doctor of Laws From Virginia State College" June 11, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1666)
    - "The election of Oliver W. Hill To the City Council of Richmond, Va." June 18, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1666)
    - "The Voting Activities of Certain Virginia Teachers" June 25, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1666)
    - "How Shall We Vote In The Forthcoming Presidential Election?" July 9, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1667)
    - "The Doctrines of States' Rights: A Truth or A Fancy?" July 16, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1667)
    - "The Position of Booker T. Washington On The Subject of Participation In Politics" July 23, 1948 (Box-folder 66:1667)
  - B. News Articles: Various Papers
    - "A paper report about a man named "Devereux Jarrat" n.d. (Box-folder 66:1668)
    - "Petersburg In The Time of George Washington" n.d. (Box-folder 66:1669)
    - "Methods and Conditions of Slave labor" n.d. (Box-folder 66:1670)
    - "The Rise And Success of Negro Insurance Companies" May, 1940 (Box-folder 66:1671)
    - "The Petersburg (VA) Negro Business Association" n.d. (Box-folder 66:1672)
    - "The Virginia Negro Barber In The Days of Slavery" Feb.5, 1942 (Box-folder 66:1673)
    - "The Striving of The Negro In Fredericksburg During The Days of Slavery" Feb. 9, 1942 (Box-folder 66:1674)
    - "A Basis For Interracial Cooperation And Development In Petersburg, Virginia" July 1, 1944 (Box-folder 66:1675)
    - "The Virginia Background of Joseph Jenkins Roberts" Feb. 24, 1947 (Box-folder 66:1676)
    - Free Negroes Acquiring Property 1790-1830 (Box-folder 66:1677)
    - Untitled Article n.d. (Box-folder 66:1678)
    - "Abstract of Free Negro Labor and Property Holding In Virginia, 1830-1860, A Dissertation Submitted To The Faculty of The Division of The Social Sciences In Candidacy For The Degree Of Doctor Of Philosophy" August, 1937 (Box-folder 66:1679)
    - Untitled Article n.d. (Box-folder 66:1680)
  - C. Articles in Journals
    - "The Educational Efforts of the Freedmen's Bureau And Freedmen's Aid Societies in South Carolina, 1862-1872" May 8,1922 (Box-folder 66:1681)
    - "The Plantation Mission And Negro Religious Instruction" June 5, 1929 (Box-folder 66:1682)
    - "Negro Enterprise in Norfolk During the Days of Slavery" April, 1939 (Box-folder 66:1683)
    - "The Voteless School Teachers of Virginia" Oct. 24, 1941 (Box-folder 66:1684)
    - "Virginia Negro Soldiers and Seamen In The American Revolution" May 24, 1942 (Box-folder 66:1685)
    - "The Opportunities of Negro College Professors Research In The South" May 24, 1942 (Box-folder 66:1686)
    - "Unexplored Fields In The History of The Negro In The United States" Oct. 29, 1944 (Box-folder 66:1687)
    - "Citizenship Training: A Neglected Area In Adult Education" May 16, 1945 (Box-folder 66:1688)
    - "Virginia and The Civil Rights Program" n.d. (Box-folder 66:1689)
    - "Registration" n.d. (Box-folder 66:1690)
    - n.d. Untitled Article (Box-folder 66:1691)
    - "One Hundred and Fifty years of Business Enterprise Among the Negroes of Petersburg" Oct. 1940 (Box-folder 66:1692)
    - The Work of the Association and the People n.d. (Box-folder 66:1693)
    - The Journal of the Negro History Digested Jan. 1916 (Box-folder 66:1694)
    - "The Negro In The Virginia Navy of The American Revolution" n.d. (Box-folder 66:1695)
  - D. Addresses (speeches)
    - The Struggle of the Negro for Freedom n.d. (Box-folder 67:1696)
    - History of Gillfield Baptist Church, to 1860 n.d. (Box-folder 67:1697)
    - Government Activity and Racial Security 1932 (Box-folder 67:1698)
    - Educating The Child for Citizenship 1927 (Box-folder 67:1699)
    - The Negro in Virginia History 1938 (Box-folder 67:1700)
    - The Call for The Highly Educated 1939 (Box-folder 67:1701)
    - Unexplored Funds In The History of The Negro In The United States 1941 (Box-folder 67:1702)
    - The Virginia and Civil Rights 1949 (Box-folder 67:1703)
    - The Threatened Political and Economic Insecurity of The Negro n.d. (Box-folder 67:1704)
    - Instrumental Music and Church Worship n.d. (Box-folder 67:1705)
    - Near Great Negroes n.d. (Box-folder 67:1706)
    - Thurgood Marshall n.d. (Box-folder 67:1707)
    - Preparing For Citizenship Responsibilities Through Education n.d. (Box-folder 67:1708)
    - The College Bred Man and Negro Business n.d. (Box-folder 67:1709)
    - Negro Achievement In Petersburg from 1861-1929 n.d. (Box-folder 67:1710)
    - Improving The Economic Status of The Negro Through overnment Participation 1938 (Box-folder 67:1711)
    - The Fight For Freedom n.d. (Box-folder 67:1712)
    - Dialogue On the History of the Negro in Richmond, VA n.d. (Box-folder 67:1713)
    - "Negro Citizenship" 1934 (Box-folder 67:1714)
    - Untitled Papers n.d. (Box-folder 67:1715)
  - E. Papers, Reports, and Lecture Notes
    - House to House Campaign Skits 1939 (Box-folder 67:1716)
    - Development of Political Parties n.d. (Box-folder 67:1717)
    - No Title n.d. (Box-folder 67:1718)
    - No Title 1945 (Box-folder 67:1719)
    - No Title n.d. (Box-folder 67:1720)
    - No Title n.d. (Box-folder 67:1721)
    - No Title n.d. (Box-folder 67:1722)
    - No Title n.d. (Box-folder 67:1723)
    - Salary Needs of Chesterfield County Negro Teachers 1940 (Box-folder 67:1724)
    - Lecture Notes n.d. (Box-folder 67:1725)
    - Background of American Federalism n.d. (Box-folder 67:1726)
- SERIES VII. MATERIAL WRITTEN BY LUTHER P. JACKSON, SR.
  - F. Unpublished Works